[Music]
Hello and welcome to this session on the
business central AI resources. My name
is Peter Bo and I'm the product manager
uh in the developer platform including
the developer tools for co-pilot in
business central and with me today I
have Enrico Chibitan. He's a senior uh
software engineer on various
integrations including
copilot. So, Business Central AI
resources is part of the developer tools
for co-pilot in Business Central that
you should already be using uh if you're
building AI features in Business
Central. This is also what we call the
Microsoft managed AI resources in the
past. And in this release, we're moving
BC or Business Central AI resources from
private preview, that means by
invitation only, uh to a public preview
available for all of you. And we are
adding consumptionbased uh direct
billing of customers uh AI resource use
as well. So what is business central AI
resources? Well, it's a key feature of
the developer tools uh for co-pilot in
business central. uh publishers can use
the large language uh models via
Microsoft managed uh Azure OpenAI
resources and that eliminates the needs
for the publishers to independently uh
procure and manage the Azure OpenAI
subscriptions uh for customers
themselves.
You can still bring your own Azure Open
AAI subscription though. Um the Business
Central AI resources will be the default
and recommended approach, but some
publishers or customers might have
special needs and we'll talk more about
that later that require them to use
their own Azure Open AI subscription
uh when running the features in
production.
uh and nevertheless partners still need
to use their own subscription when they
are prototyping, developing and testing
and troubleshooting in non-production uh
and nonsas environments for instance in
containers. So just to summarize this in
an overview, copilot features in the
base application and in other Microsoft
extensions as well as the business
central uh platform co-pilot features
like chat and and analysis assist they
use the BC AI resources already today
either directly or through uh the uh
developer tools if it's AL code based
features and until now your application
has been using your own Ashure OpenAI
subscription unless you were part of the
private preview of course but that was
not in in production also. So what
changes now is that going forward the
recommendation is that your co-pilot
features uses the business central AI
resources in production environments as
uh
well and uh so you see this will sort of
be the norm that you call through uh the
toolkit and access the business central
AI resources. You can still use your own
Azure OpenAI resource um subscription as
we talked about before. Uh but again
mostly or recommended only for uh
development or for um special
needs. So what are the benefits of using
the business central AI resources? Well,
first of all um you can take advantage
of reduced operational overhead. So that
means that you avoid uh the need to
manage um or handle the infrastructure
yourself. So that could be you know
updates, monitoring, troubleshooting or
maintenance of the Azure OpenAI
subscription that allows you to free up
your resources to add value in core
business um operations and IP for the
customers
instead. It also simplifies the
onboarding of building AI based features
in Business Central. So you can quickly
integrate uh these capabilities in your
solutions. It also gives an improved
reliability because uh someone that
means us will proactively ensure that
resources are scaled and throttled and
have load balancing and fault tolerance
uh measures etc. that ensures a
consistent performance during peak uh
demand among customers.
It also gives a more streamlined
experience for customers uh because they
will have a more seamless AI uh resource
management is going to be the same
across all different ISV solutions that
a customer uses and also the customers
will have a unified consumptionbased
billing experience across ISV solutions
and lastly it will also give you the
benefit of enhanced security compliance.
So uh when you use the business central
ARI resources there will be built-in
compliance measures and uh governance
that helps uh protecting against harmful
and malicious uh content and just
general compliance uh with data uh
residency. So maybe Enrico can you talk
a little bit more about those last
safety measures? Yes, of course. Thank
you
Peter. So um I'm going to talk about
again what means content safety for us.
So this is of course something that we
apply to our own calls to Azure OpenAI
through the um Microsoft Business
Central AI resources. But this will also
apply to you the moment you start using
them. And we have um um like very
optimized setup where we use a blocking
policy. So if you have setup before your
Asia open subscription, you know that
you can have policies applied on a
subscription level. That means basically
that um you decide what type of content
and what level of filtering should be
applied to the calls to the large
language model. So we use a blocking
policy as I mentioned which means we
actually block calls that trigger
content safety filters and we have all
the filters about uh hate violence,
sexual content, self harm that are kind
of the default that Asure OpenAI um
offers but we include also some Jbreak
detection and we have uh already some
basic cross prompt injection injection
attack protection but we have uh in the
plans to have some even better
protection. So this is actually a point
that I want to stress which is these are
the same policies and the same content
safety that we use at Microsoft which
means is um what we think is the safest
for our customers um and also is applied
to what you um are doing by using the
toolkit. So we're just using the same
and one point that I always like to stop
for a second on is um this is all about
the content safety but um related to
security and privacy. We get a lot of
questions especially from customers but
also from some of you. Um and the
questions are okay we are using the
Microsoft AI to get AI resources but is
Microsoft going to use this data to
train models for example or is this data
going to be saved somewhere and the
answer is we care about your data and
your data is your data so no we're not
using data to train models uh we're not
using data for example um to like
improve Microsoft services and such uh
we just use it for the purpose that you
and that your code uh needs. So you can
read more of course on the Asia OpenAI
website and we just comply to of course
all the Asia OpenAI um
guidelines. So let's move to the next
section and see how you can actually use
the business central AI resources versus
bring your own Asia OpenAI subscription
in the toolkit.
So the um first of all you can find
samples in case you have not yet started
developing your own copilot feature in
our
aka.ms/bct. We have a full folder which
is samples as openai which contains a
few different samples you can have a
look at and you can get started with
these are already ready to be deployed
in your test environment just to see how
the code works and to have a look at how
you can get um started from
something. These are already using um
the Microsoft Business Central AI
toolkit resources and the point in the
code that is doing this is this exact
line of code which is set manage
resource authorization. This is also as
Peter said our recommended way of um
connecting to the large language model
in the back end. So you will see this
line of code in our samples and you
should use this line of code in your own
features and as you can see it requires
two additional parameters which are the
second and third um which is the Asia
OpenAI account name and Asia OpenAI API
key. So for the moment being we still
require you as a partner to have an
active Azure OpenAI subscription and
this is mostly to make sure that you are
um allowed to use Azure OpenAI and you
are compliant and have accepted the
Azure OpenAI terms of usage.
um this is just a requirement that we
have but only for um checking that you
have access. We don't actually consume
your resources. So that also means you
don't really need to have um deployed
models which also cost money just to
have even if you don't use them um you
just need to have a a an approved u
subscription and that's
enough as you can see. Also the last
parameter here is um get GPD for our
latest which is like the deployment name
that you're going to use which aka you
can also call the model name. We offer a
few different models and you can find
them in the Azure AOI deployments code
unit.
As Peter mentioned, we also support
bringing your own Asia open subscription
which is uh needed when you are
developing for example or also
troubleshooting and so on and also for
very specific cases u in case there is
some feature that we don't yet support
in the business central AI toolkit
resources. Uh in that case you just need
instead of the function I showed in the
previous slide you need to use this set
authorization function instead.
So, I mentioned a few times that when
you're developing, you need to use your
own subscription and then you need um or
we would like you to move to the
Microsoft subscription when you deploy
your um solution to production. But how
does this look like in code? Because a
question we get a lot is do I need then
to have two types um or two versions of
code, one for testing and one for
deploying to production? And the answer
is you don't necessarily need that. So,
you can actually have them in the same
code.
And the way we recommend you do this is
you just while you're developing in your
docking docker container or for example
in your on premise um test environment
you can just use the um bring your own
subscription and you can do this with
the switch based on whether you are in
SAS infrastructure or not. So as you can
see in this code sample I am using this
environment information code unit for
that purpose. We have also collected a
few questions that we got from some of
you in the last few events. For example,
in the event we had last month with a
few partners um just specifically about
AI and uh we just want to like go
through them just to make sure that some
of the most commonly asked questions are
covered. For example, are my calls using
the toolkit staying in my geography? And
the answer is uh whenever possible, yes.
So we as Microsoft of course commit to
data privacy. So your data will stay
within geography if there is the option.
In some cases though we don't have an
Asia open AAI um like deployment or data
center in the same geography. In these
cases the administrator of the tenant
can just decide to not allow calls
across geography and they can just turn
it off from a centralized place which is
the copilot and agent capabilities page
in business central. Also we quickly
mentioned that there are additional
system prompts when you're using the
toolkit. Um so this is part of our
content safety um or um yeah in general
uh AI safety um measures and uh we
append uh meta prompt as we call it to
your own prompts. So this actually might
change slightly the behavior between
your testing in on premise uh
environment and your deployment to
production. So we always recommend that
you do all the development and testing
on premise with your own Azure Open
subscription and then you do thorough
testing on uh um kind of sandbox
environment before you actually start
deploying this to your customers because
again um the u the the output using
business central resources might be in
some cases slightly different. One more
thing you might have noticed is that
there are new models coming out all the
time from Asure OpenAI and we use always
um the newest model that we think fits
the purpose which means sometimes models
are deprecated. When that happens you
receive if you have set up developer
telemetry on your extension you receive
a telemetry signal that tells you on
your app inside app inside subscription
that one of the models is being
deprecated. So then you should move to
the new model and test that your prompts
and that your setup still works with the
new model. We have some slightly
stricter deadlines with the model
deprecations than we have with AL
deprecation. So uh just make sure you do
the testing before the model is actually
deprecated. Otherwise we might just move
you to the new model if the old one is
no longer available. So we will not
break your feature. We will try to move
it to the new model. But again,
different models might behave
differently. So your feature might just
not work as well with the new one.
Another question we get a lot is whether
you can use the data source capabilities
that Azure OpenAI exposes from our
toolkit. That is currently not possible.
Neither by using the AI resources from
the toolkit nor by bringing your own
Azure OpenI subscription. Every time we
received this question, we tried to
understand what the use case of the
partner was. And most in most of the
cases, we actually found other ways to
um to basically reach the same effect
that didn't really need data sources.
But if you think you have a use case
where this is actually needed, please
let us know and add it to
aka.ms/bcid. And the last frequently
asked question I have is whether um we
can expose non open AI models in our
toolkit for example deepseek or other
models that have come out recently. And
the answer is we don't support that
currently and that's because we only
expose to your partners capabilities
that we as Microsoft use. And that's
because of course we want to keep them
tested and make sure that they work uh
before we actually like give them uh to
the partners. So uh currently no but you
can of course once again suggest this on
aka.ms/bc ideas and let us know um what
is your use case and with this I'll pass
it on to Peter again to talk about
billing. Thank you Enrico. Yeah, let's
talk about billing of AI resources. Um,
I mean that calls to to to LLMs in your
solutions. If you're using your own
Azure Open AI subscription, you likely
run into some challenges uh with
managing billing across uh your
customers. So, uh let's let's imagine
that um we have a customer here uh who
is running on a um on an environment
with multiple ISV solutions deployed. So
we have three ISV solutions here. Uh so
they're from three different uh ISVS and
then these ISVS have um co-pilot
features in their uh solutions all of
them. So they each have their own
copilot um sorry Azure open AAI
subscription that they manage for their
solution which means that they need to
charge uh each um the customer for the
customer's consumption in their solution
right so that means that the customers
will get uh three different um uh
billing uh experiences uh out of this
which is not that convenient uh for for
the customers uh to to handle. Um
likewise hopefully uh an ISV has
multiple customers maybe hundreds of
customers but likely only a single
shared Azure Open AI subscription
because you know they're reusing the
same uh app source and you connect to to
one instance in that and that means that
when many of these different users are
actually consuming the uh resources in
the ISV's own subscription the ISV needs
to um track that consumption and make
sure that they can split uh or or build
the customers individually based on each
customer's use uh of the copilot
features in the ISV's IP. So that's
gives an overhead of of
management and maybe they even need uh
the ISV have so much success that they
even need to scale their Azure open
subscription. So they they have to sort
of manage that with the Azure load
balancer or the Azure traffic manager or
regional instances etc. So there can be
a lot of management involved in um
supporting customers uh with an ISV
subscription. Let's have a look at how
billing works when using Business
Central AI resources. So this will be a
consumptionbased uh approach where the
customers will build directly from
Microsoft. However, the details of that
uh is not ready at the time of this
recording. Um but keep an eye out for
details after launch to learn more about
how the billing works. So let's have a
summary of the differences between uh
the business central AI resources and uh
when you bring your own Azure open AI
subscription. If we look at deployment
and environments first then when you use
the business central AI resources
Microsoft manages those
resources but it also means that it's
available in SAS only and production
environments only. If you bring your own
Azure OpenAI in subscription, you must
handle everything around deployment uh
of the models, keep them up to date, uh
you know, take care of regions,
geography, data residency, etc. You will
be charged for models u even if you're
not using them. Um but it also means
that you can use this both in SAS but
also in non-SAS environments. And so
this will still be uh recommended for
development and testing in your uh sort
of onremise and container uh
setups. If we look at the differences uh
when it comes to models then when you're
using the business central AI resources
uh the production ready models that are
available are GBT 40 and 40 mini. Um we
will likely add more in the future but
those are the ones that are available at
the time of recording.
uh we will notify you if you opt into
telemetry about when new models are
coming and old models are obsoleted. Um
also at the time of the recording we do
not support uh embeddings although we
have plans in probably next release uh
in a you know half a year to a year's
time frame to provide some semantic
search capabilities that are similar to
embeddings.
If you bring your own Azure OpenAI
subscription, you have a choice of all
the models available there whether they
are uh from the OpenAI. So uh you know
could be 01 or 03 mini the reasoning
models but it could also be deepseek or
Gemini or other models available there.
Um but it also means that you manage
those models and you need to follow
duplication timelines etc. You can there
do embeddings and fine-tuning depending
on your model. Um and as Enrico
mentioned uh in you know regardless of
whether you use the business center AI
resources or your own subscription it's
not possible to bring your own data
sources to for instance uh use Azure AI
search for for retrieval augmented uh
generation. If we look at the major
differences in responsible AI uh for the
business central AI resources as Enrico
mentioned we have the content filters
and some additions to the system
prompts. Uh when you have your own Azure
OpenAI subscription you also have
content filters but you have more uh
choice on how to set those up. uh we
still apply even for your subscription
some uh system prompt uh mechanism for
uh for that in SAS uh but of course if
you're running uh in on premise you need
to write your own uh management of that
or handling of that and then when we
talk about billing then when you use the
Microsoft central AI resources Microsoft
will charge to customers directly when
they use AI uh based on their
consumption uh customers will be able to
track usage search, set limits, and get
a single detail invoice across all of
the ISVS that are using Business Central
AI resources for their copilot
features. Then what you can do or
probably will do hopefully is that you
charge your IP uh the way you do it
today, right? So you can use the apps
source um transactability feature or you
can have your own custom uh licensing
for your applications. If you bring or
use your own Azure OpenAI subscription
customers, you need to track everything
around consumption and you need to
manage the building across uh customers.
So um to end this session uh I just want
to raise the awareness that on uh
YouTube our YouTube uh channel we
actually have a number of different
playlists and one of the playlists is on
extending co-pilot uh in Business
Central. So that covers all of the
capabilities that you have for building
copilot features inside of Business
Central. how you use the developer tools
for building uh prompt dialogues, how
you do tests, etc. So, um if you haven't
worked with building copilot features in
Business Central, I recommend that you
go there and watch uh those recordings.
Thank you for joining this session.
Thank you.